I'm here not to tell you that Canonical is pivoting to becoming an AI company,
but to tell you that it's been here all along.
Ubuntu powers the majority of today's AI workloads.
Unfortunately, I think I am going to contribute to the AI native dev eye test
because I have dark slides and light slides, so apologies for that.
As Alan said, I'm Jon. I'm the VP of Engineering for Ubuntu.
I've been at Canonical for five years.
In that time, I've mostly worked on cloud native orchestration-type tools,
but in the last year, I've been working on this little open-source project
that some of you might have heard of called Ubuntu.
I'm here not to tell you that Canonical is pivoting to becoming an AI company.
I don't think that's the case.
It's certainly not in my immediate roadmap,
but to tell you that it's been here all along, in a sense.
Ubuntu has been here for the last 21 years, 22 years,
and I suspect it will be here for the next 20 years
if we don't make any huge mistakes in the coming probably three to four years.
We are in the privileged position where I can say this today,
which is that Ubuntu powers the majority of today's AI workloads.
You might ask, why is that?
Some of it is because the wonderful agents that we have today,
when you ask them how you do something, are really good at saying,
on Ubuntu, sometimes on Ubuntu or Debian, type this command.
And I think that is a representation of the fact that for 20 years,
the orange Linux has been the one that people reach for.
That is a combination of exceptional strategy
from the previous people at Canonical and a healthy dollop of luck.
But when you launch cloud instances today,
most of you probably don't care what kind of Linux you get,
but it's probably our one in reality.
It doesn't matter whether you're on Google Cloud,
whether you're on Amazon, whether you're on DigitalOcean,
or Volta, or Hetzner, or whatever you like.
If you launch a VM, there's a good chance it's going to be Ubuntu.
Whether or not we are, in fact,
at the hallowed year of the Linux desktop,
we have very much been year of the Linux server
for many, many years.
But none of those things are particularly new.
Those have been facts for some time.
It's long before I got involved with Ubuntu.
One of the things that I think is really fascinating
in this particular era,
is something that no one really talks about,
because it's not glamorous, it's not glitzy,
it doesn't get great headlines on Reddit and Phoronix,
where they like to tell us that our choices are wrong
for choosing Rust and such.
But it's actually our very, very strong partner business.
So we're actually a pretty small company
in the enterprise Linux game.
We're about 1,300 people,
of which about 1,000 are engineers.
When I joined five years ago, we were 550 in total.
But the fact remains that SUSE is,
I think, five times our size,
and Red Hat is 25 times our size,
if you ignore the big IBM-shaped thing on the side of it.
So we are relatively little,
but I think we punch well above our weight
when it comes to working with the people you see on screen,
and more.
So I couldn't get all of the logos on here,
but there's lots of fun ones,
like MediaTek and RivOS, and all these things.
And this makes a huge difference,
because this means when you go down
to whichever consumer electronics store you want,
or whichever internet business you buy your computer from,
and you want to play with AI stuff,
you want to get working with it,
you open the lid, and it is actually going to work.
This is particularly true of NVIDIA hardware
in recent months,
but we are expanding massively with AMD.
We have always done lots of work with Intel.
And with things like Qualcomm Dragonwing,
which is one of their kind of edge IoT platforms,
we were right there on launch day, good to go,
with support in the kernel,
support for all of the accelerators, right?
Not just the CPU and GPU,
but all of the NPUs and TPUs,
and sort of star PUs that they're starting to introduce.
And this, I think, was a pretty big moment.
So there's this little Silicon company called NVIDIA
that some of you will have heard of,
and they released an ARM64-only AI workstation
called the NVIDIA DGX Spark,
to much applause in the late part of last year.
And what was different about this for us
is NVIDIA have shipped Ubuntu for years,
and they've done that in agreement with us,
and it's been called DGX OS,
or it's been called NVIDIA something OS,
but it's been Ubuntu with a bunch of stuff installed
and some different kernel configurations.
And what changed for this is they just ship Ubuntu
and they call it Ubuntu.
And it is not only do they ship Ubuntu and call it Ubuntu,
it is the only thing they will support on the DGX Spark.
Now, I don't have all of their product roadmap,
and I don't know what's coming up,
but I'd take a pretty good educated guess
that in the future, their other workstations,
so this is the Grace Blackwell architecture,
also seen sold by Dell, and I think Lenovo,
and possibly HP, all of them run Ubuntu.
And the reason they run Ubuntu
is because they can boot Ubuntu on it,
and it just works.
Like all of the drivers are there,
the kernel behaves properly,
all of the accelerators are there.
So this was a pretty huge moment for us,
but I also think it was quite a big moment
for the AI development community,
because working in development on the operating system
that is running in your cloud,
I think is fairly obviously
and has always been fairly obviously
a bit of an advantage.
This is something I'm very excited about.
So we do a two-year LTS release.
So these are the ones
that realistically everybody runs,
something like the late 90%
of all of our users run an LTS,
and they are 22.04, 24.04,
and the one coming out in April is 26.04.
And for the first time,
you will be able to apt install CUDA
or apt install ROCm
with no other commands on a base Ubuntu system
and get exactly the version of ROCm
that works with your version of Ubuntu
and your GPU with no messing about.
And having personally suffered through this
with a collection of quite high-end AMD machines
and various versions of ROCm
and the driver and various other things,
and I'm told it is equally as painful in CUDA land,
I think this is kind of a big deal.
And it also speaks to that cloud story as well.
In reality, all of the clouds
are also running these big shiny green GPUs
in their data centres
and not investing engineering time
in trying to work out
how to get the latest version of CUDA
security-maintained for 15 years,
which is our kind of promise,
I think is a pretty big thing.
And it's particularly big
for developers getting started in this industry.
Lots of you will already know
how to wrangle CUDA into shape
and make ROCm work with PyTorch.
Good for you.
If you have any ideas,
do please let me know.
But I think it's going to get a lot easier
because of this.
It's just going to be out of the box, essentially.
Having said that we're not an AI company,
because I don't think we are, in quotes,
an AI company,
we have released something relatively new
which is distinctly kind of an AI product.
Not a product in the sense
that we are monetising it
and selling it to you.
A product in the sense
that you can go and get it
and use it, it's open source
and we built it.
I think this is really interesting
for the hobbyist, the tinkerer,
the developer at the moment.
But I think it has huge potential
to go further than that.
So in the world of Linux packaging
and the microcosm of internet culture
that that is,
there are these things called snaps.
Most people in the world
don't care that there is a thing called snaps.
It is a packaging format.
It is a packaging format we invented
and it has some interesting properties
in many, many applications
on the internet and in computing.
But those exact same properties
make it especially interesting,
I think, in the world of AI.
So snaps are a confined package format.
Unlike a deb where you apt instal
or an RPM package where you dnf instal
or whatever it is,
a snap is a little bit more
like a docker container.
It is a compressed file system
full of an application
and all of its dependencies.
But critically,
it runs in a security-confined environment.
So we use the AppArmor Linux security module
which is a bit like SE Linux
for those of you
that have been in the Linux space.
And that means that you can instal a snap
with all kinds of scary stuff in it
and run it and not worry about it
doing wild things to your machine.
Does this sound familiar in the AI space?
So we started distributing these things
called inference snaps.
And this is a bit of a play
towards how do we make this stuff easy
for people to get working with.
At the moment,
it's all very fun
to be at the very cutting edge
playing on Hugging Face
and looking at the rankings
and trying to work out
which model is going to fit on your GPU.
And do I want Lama CPP
or do I not want Lama CPP?
The 90% AI engineer,
if not now in the next six months,
is going to be like,
give me the model.
I've heard of Gemma.
I've heard of Nemetron.
I've heard of Quen.
How do I play with it
without getting a PhD in Hugging Face?
So that's what we've done.
Inference snaps are high quality
silicon-optimised AI models for everybody.
And this goes a bit back
to my previous statement.
The key here
is they are actually optimised
by the silicon company.
So we are partnering with AMD
and NVIDIA and Intel and whoever.
When we first started talking about this,
no one was really interested
and when we launched the first one,
everyone started kicking our door down.
So we are slowly rolling out more models.
But the gist of it is
you can, on any Ubuntu machine in the world,
type snap instal Quen VL,
snap instal DeepSeq R1,
snap instal Gemma 3,
Nemetron 3 Nano,
and what you will get
is a working model
that has been optimised
for the hardware on your machine
by the people who built the silicon,
delivered by us and maintained by us.
And it doesn't just come
with the model itself
because, again, what do you do
if you just download the model
in its bare form?
Not super interesting.
It comes in a silicon-optimised form
with the right inference engine
for that model
according to the manufacturer.
And it gives you
this super nice onboarding
if you just want to play
with local AI models.
You want to hook them up to Olama.
You want to hook them up
to, like, Continue,
whatever it is you might want to do.
This is the kind of, like,
gory guts of it diagram.
There's a lot going on here,
but it's actually relatively simple.
So the snap, the big orange box,
is the SquashFS file system
inside which is stuff, right?
And we have this thing
called an engine manager
which is shared
between all of our inference snaps.
The engine manager
has some nice capabilities
like understanding what a machine is,
what API level your card supports,
that kind of thing.
We have engine manifests
which describe the different kinds
of things you might be,
like you're an AMD GPU,
you're an NVIDIA-capable,
sorry, a CUDA-capable NVIDIA GPU.
And then we have the inference engine
which is kind of swappable,
could be Lama CPP,
could be something else,
and the runtime of the model.
And all of that is hooked up
kind of automatically
when you instal it
through the snap confinement
so it kind of punches
just enough hole
through the confinement
to speak to the kernel
and get what it needs
about the machine.
But the outcome is this.
You can snap instal QuenVL
and then you can QuenVL chat.
And in your terminal,
wouldn't be a Linux talk
without some terminal chat,
but in your terminal
you can chat with the model.
We've got four of these
at the moment.
This is the least interesting thing
you could do with it.
It is also,
every single one of them
comes with an open AI
API spec compatible endpoint, right?
Just running on local host
on a port.
Each of them comes
on a distinct port
so you can co-instal them.
Some of them can be running
one engine and runtime.
Some of them can be running another.
You could have,
if you've got a big honking machine
with a bunch of GPUs in it,
you can have one running
on your ROCm capable AMD card.
You could have one running
on your CUDA capable NVIDIA card.
That's not a problem.
And basically anything
that can speak the open AI
API spec will be able
to speak to this thing.
All of the,
I'll do a little demo
of this at the end.
All of the examples on here
are talking to local host,
but there is nothing
to stop you slapping a caddy proxy
in front of this
and sticking it on a cloud machine
with a big honking H100 in it
or something like that
and using it.
So this,
assuming you have access
to cloud machinery
that has access to Ubuntu,
which is I think everybody,
then you can make use
of this immediately.
But it's particularly fun
to play with on a machine
that has some capability.
Unfortunately,
when I do the demo,
I'm talking to you
on a thing that has
absolutely no acceleration
whatsoever, so it's real slow.
But I promise you,
it's cool on a machine
that's a little bit quicker
than my laptop.
The other thing
that I think
as the de facto operating system
for a bunch of engineers
is sandboxing agents.
I am probably preaching
to the choir in here
when I say that they were,
the agents have clearly been
a big step up
in the capability.
Like that is the lived experience
for lots of people
I speak to in my job,
but also my own experience.
It went from,
hey, there's this cool bot
I can talk to in my browser
to, okay,
I actually have
like a fleet of robots
that can half do
some of the boring stuff
and actually some
of the more interesting stuff
for me.
And I think it's difficult
to imagine,
I imagine lots of you
in a position
where it's kind of difficult
to imagine going back
to doing certain classes
of work without an agent.
Like you're sitting there going,
why was I ever doing this myself?
You're probably also
reading the horror stories
on Reddit,
sort of laughing and going,
ha ha, that user did something silly.
It deleted their home directory
because they're idiots.
And also in the back
of your mind going,
what if it deletes
my home directory?
I have personally not had
any of those big fails,
but I did have a fun one
recently where a set
of parallel agents
were set off by Claude,
which as part
of a build process
or something else,
decided to build five copies
of Node.js from source,
completely exhausted the memory
on my cloud server,
which resulted
in Tailsgale being um-killed
and me no longer being able
to talk to it.
Not catastrophic data loss,
but kind of annoying.
And so lots of the agents
are responding to this
by telling you
you can run slash sandbox
and it's going to be fine.
It might be fine.
Like your confinement
is a tough topic.
It is something
that we have been doing
for years
with our snap packages,
for years with AppArmor,
for years with virtual machines
and micro VMs,
and chucking a big honking
Node.js code
based on someone's machine
and wrapping it
with bubble wrap
with a thousand exceptions,
not that handy.
It prevents some failures,
and that's why
the vast majority
of you probably haven't
had an epic fail
and lived the YOLO life,
dangerously skipped
whatever it is,
and are mostly okay.
But I'm sure
you've all experienced
doing something
you'd rather not have done,
but you're all sensible
and responsible,
so recover from it just fine.
No tears.
The good news is
we have a bunch of stuff
that is out of the box
on pretty much
every Ubuntu machine
on the planet
that just makes this
pretty simple.
We actually have
a really cool product
which is one of the only things
I have worked on in five years
that is not yet open source.
We will announce in April
which I think is going to
blow the doors off this thing.
But it is built on top
of all the things
I'm going to talk about today.
So one of which is LexD.
This is a product
that until I worked at Canonical
I had no idea about,
and about six months
after I worked at Canonical
I couldn't work out
why nobody was talking about it.
It is in the category
of something
that should be boring
but I think is very cool.
LexD is a clustered version of LexC
which is a decade old
piece of containerisation technology
in the Linux kernel.
It lets you get
Linux system containers
which are a bit like
a Docker container
but feel a bit more like a VM.
So it's a container
but it also runs systemd.
And so it's much,
it's kind of heavier weight
than a Docker container
but it still doesn't have
its own kernel.
And it also does virtual machines.
And the API
is basically identical
like LexC launch
and then you can LexC launch
dash dash VM
but all of the other
dash dashes and configures
exactly the same.
But if you want a situation
where actually you'd prefer
a kernel, another kernel
in between you and the agent
for a little bit more separation
you can do that.
Personally I switch
between the two
depending on what project
I'm working on
and the source code I'm writing.
Sometimes I launch a VM,
sometimes I launch a container.
The script is identical
apart from one flag.
And this is broadly
how I've been using
Claw Code for the last few months.
So I have a little tiny script.
It's only about six lines
and it basically
creates LXD container
the image for which
is already cached.
It mounts my local
working directory
into the container
as a bind mount.
It mounts my .clawed directory
and a couple of .files
and starts Ubuntu
and Claw Code
and it takes about
three or four seconds
for a cache.
So I just type
CC here, Claw Code here
and I get Claw Code
in a box
just talking to my project
and it can basically run while.
It can't make commits
because I have to tap
my YubiKey for that
but I can just let it
do what it wants,
set five of them off.
You can set
all the usual constraints
like CPUs and memory
it can use
with or without a VM layer.
And this is just installed.
It's literally ready to go
on every Ubuntu machine
out of the box.
It's just there.
So I'd implore you
to go and take a look at it.
It's on all of the cloud instances
that you're already
hosting your stuff on
and it makes a really nice
little kind of wrapper
around these tools.
We also have Multipass.
Multipass is like
the Docker desktop thing
in our portfolio.
You can instal Multipass
on your Mac,
on your Windows machine
and of course
on your Linux machine.
You get a nice UI
and it's just the fastest way
to get Ubuntu anywhere.
You Multipass launch
and you will be at a Multipass,
at an Ubuntu shell
in two or three seconds
and that is a disposable machine
you can just
crap all over
or an agent can crap all over
and then you can get rid of it.
It's got all of our
different versions.
You can do blueprints
and recipes
and things like that
but it has this nice kind of
Docker desktop style feel
that's a bit more orange
that you can use
for getting disposable
Ubuntu instances
that are running under
QMU essentially.
So that's the kind of
development side.
We describe Multipass
as a bit of a cloud sandbox
which is a nice
kind of segue into
well what about
once you finish building
your shiny thing,
your hundreds of thousands
of lines of TypeScript
or Rust or Go
whatever it is
that your agent
has been diligently
coding for you.
How do you launch it?
How do you deploy it?
Again a question
that we have been dealing with
for 20 or so years
of production Linux
and
working at Canonical
is kind of a really
interesting experience
because literally everybody
knows about Ubuntu
and basically nobody
has heard of Canonical
or any of their other products
but like LexD
we have all of these other
kind of interesting things
which again I think are
genuinely coming into their own
as we head into this era
of there's a whole bunch
of like semi-autonomous
things going off
and we want to
we want to use them
to the best of our ability
we want them to run
as fast and efficiently
as possible
but we also want
to have some
we want to have some
guarantees around that
we want to know
what they can mess with
that if we set them off
in production
they will continue
to be patched
for 15 years
even if the vendor
disappears in the AI boom
like some of the vendors
that we love
lovingly talk about
right now
I suspect might not be here
in five years
we're at that sort of point
I think in the AI
product launch sphere
the thing that we have done
and have always done
and the only reason
I can stand here
after 22 years
of Ubuntu being
a big open source project
is because we have done
the long term support
security maintenance
patching work
that lets other people
do the exciting work
on Linux for years
and that applies here too
and we have this
nice initiative
that we've called
sort of like LTS anything
and essentially
you can come to us
with a Docker container
we come to an agreement
on what that's going to cost
but we will literally
security maintain that thing
your application
and all of its dependencies
even if that's thousands
of Python dependencies
or tens of thousands
of node dependencies
we will keep patching
that thing for CVEs
for 15 years for you
for a cost
all based on Ubuntu
and the work that we do
for keeping the archive running
and keeping all those servers going
and then we have a suite
of kind of automation stuff
Kubeflow for example
we have a one command
deploy Kubeflow
that works on any Kubernetes
it works on EKS
it works on AKS
it works on our Kubernetes
you can literally
one shot a Kubeflow
for yourself
play around with it
and then destroy it
and not lose any sleep
the same for MLflow
the same for OpenSearch
if you want a vector database
the same for Postgres
and so while we don't necessarily
directly pedal
the newest shiniest AI thing
we're not building agents
we're not building models
we're not training models
we kind of very competently
take care of all the stuff
that that stuff relies on
in a very safe secure
kind of stop worrying about it
sort of way
so that's the end of my slides
I thought I would give you
a little demo
of the inference snaps
it's a slow demo
so it's going to
maybe I should just slow down
my talking
but this is the CLI
so you can take a look
at the status of this thing
this is the Gemma3 snap
so that's Gemma3 from Google
you could also do the same
for Nemotron
which is mostly for NVIDIA stuff
and each of these
has a nice kind of
concept of what it supports
and what it doesn't
so you can see here
Nemotron has the concept
of a CPU engine
which is obviously
going to run pretty slow
on my potato framework laptop
or you can run it
on an NVIDIA GPU
and it will scream
and it'll get the right sized
model for the GPU
that you have
and this is all
like you can instal the snap
really quickly
and the snap in the background
will go talk to our store
exchange a bit of details
of what your hardware is
and then go and essentially
fetch the right model
in the background
each of them
so we'll talk to DeepSeek
for a bit
you can do a chat thing
this is just a command line chat
so hi DeepSeek
this will then sit here
and set my laptop on fire
you can see the token rate
is pretty low
on my little AMD framework
but equally
you can open up
to things like continue
so because it speaks
all of the right APIs
like this is a little config file
I wrote for the continue
VS code extension
which gives you
your kind of self-hosted model
cloud code type experience
so you can see here
each of these
just has an API URL
which runs on local host
on a separate port
you can get the model details
from the status CLI
and then of course
you can start asking it questions
about your code
what does this do
and we can sit here
and laugh
at the token rate
that my laptop can do
and because continue
is designed for all this stuff
you can obviously just switch between them
and as we launch more models
and different optimised models
you'll just be able to kind of
turn them on and off
as you wish
and when you're not actually
talking to the thing
it consumes essentially
no resources
it's just there in the background
if you need it
like I say
I think there is a
genuine use case here
for if you are a company
that can afford
one big stinking
H100 in the cloud somewhere
and you want to do
private inference
slapping one of these
snaps on it
and a caddy proxy
in front of it
or an nginx proxy
or something like that
you're good to go
like you suddenly
are hosting an AI model
on hardware
on a machine
that you control
and you're good to go
and that
is pretty much it
does anyone
have any questions
thank you so much
John how on earth
does canonical
survive for 22 years
giving it all away
thank you very much
John Seeger
any questions
yep
let's dive straight over here
hi
I was wondering
you mentioned
how
well Ubuntu is very popular
everyone knows about it
do you think
now
with just LLMs
being all over
like all over the internet
you kind of like
are in a position
where you will
slowly just like
end up consuming
all of it
because
every LLM
will always be like
oh let's do it
Ubuntu way
blah blah blah
and therefore now
you get more code
on the internet
also using it
Ubuntu way
and
I'd say with any luck
yes
but I think
we need to not rely on luck
and so part of our job
is to work out
like how do we
keep
either how do we do deals
with the AI providers
to ensure that happens
or how do we keep
being
a default enough
in other things
that the other material
the LLMs are trained on
they know about Ubuntu
and those kind of things
like we're sort of
lucky not lucky
that that's the situation
but I think if we're not careful
we could be
you know
a Sousa
or a Red Hat
could do a big drive
on you know
having an LLMs.txt
on all of their endpoints
and like really going for it
so I think we need
to pay attention
I also think
it's very easy for
somebody who works at
Canonical on Ubuntu
to get all wound up on
which Linux distribution it is
I'm quite aware
that most people
don't care
they're like
give me a cloud instance
and it like
it is what it is
again I think
because for so long
that has been Ubuntu
lots of people
have got muscle memory
around apps instal
or whatever it might be
we just need to
basically keep that up
in the same way
that lots of marketing teams
are flapping over SEO
because AI models
work a bit differently
we have to think
a little bit differently
about how we make sure
that our content
is in the right places
in the right forms
and it's actually relevant
like I said
we're not
in quotes an AI company
but that doesn't mean
we don't have something
to say in an era
where everyone
is building with AI
so it's about
how do we position it
in a way that is
actually authentic
towards what we can
actually do
and what value
we can actually add
because it isn't
going to be competing
with Nvidia
to train models
and build GPUs
yeah I would say
I'd say pretty much
every company
wants to be having
that conversation
in our case
it's about
how do we make sure
that our lens
keep telling people
how to actually
instal RockM
yeah
cool
thanks for the great talk
I'm going to ask you
something controversial
and I'm sure
you're watching the news
and OpenAI
is now planning
to do something
operating system related
yeah
we had browser use
computer use
soon it's going to be
operating system use
yeah
what is the water cooler
chat in your organisation
and maybe
you've heard whispers
in other operating system
worlds
on this
where is this going
and what impact
does it have
great question
yes
so I don't know
I mean I wouldn't say
there's a lot of
water cooler chat
like I'm certainly
not sat in my seat
at home at the moment
going oh my goodness
OpenAI is going to
out Linux us tomorrow
I follow it with interest
like I thought
Claude Code
building a C compiler
was kind of a fun
science experiment
I'm sure you all
saw this one right
and Claude Code
built a browser
and various other things
I think what that shows
is it's a very
interesting technology
these are interesting
experiments but like
building an operating system
isn't just about
like the fun part
of building an operating system
in Ubuntu
was done 20 years ago
like the success
has come from
grinding away
patching security
vulnerabilities
doing usability studies
shipping the latest
and greatest open source
doing things that
have set the internet
on fire a little bit
like we're doing
this big rust transition
where we're replacing
all the core utilities
and sudo and the
time-sinking demon
with new rust-based
alternatives
everyone's like
oh my god
what are you doing
but like it's
those sorts of things
that have
actually meant
people have kept
using Ubuntu
like I'm sure
that Claude Code
can build an OS
like I'm absolutely
sure of it
can like
but are Anthropic
going to be in the business
of actually maintaining
an operating system
for use on
definitely tens of
if not hundreds of
millions of cloud instances
I don't know
like doesn't
doesn't seem like
their business model right
like people are still
going to want security
maintenance and rock
solid Linux I think
so at the moment
I'm not sweating
too much
cool
thank you for the
talk so I've usually run
models using
Olama
so have you noticed
any significant
performance improvement
if you use
on your local
Ubuntu
optimised version
yes because I imagine
hardware is a limiting
thing so half of it I think
is just selecting
the right model
like I'm sure
everyone has felt
the overwhelm of like
I'll go and get something
hugging faces like
okay cool
now what
what's going on
so part of it is just
we're just going to
restrict that down
like we're just going to
we're just going to say
this is you know
it's of the deep
seek R1 variety
and there's maybe
10 variants and it's
going to pick the best
one for your machine
and best one for your
machine is not only
the one that's actually
sized for your machine
but has been tuned
to some extent by the
silicon vendor
now does that mean
it's going to be
perfect for your
use case every time
probably not
does it mean it's
going to be better
for 90% of people
90% of the time
probably right
like if you are
doing something
hyper specific
in like a really
really optimised way
I'm sure it's worth
you investing time
in retuning a model
and parameterizing
and quantising it
very very specifically
but if you're like
I'd like to write
some Python
I'd like to get some
help from an AI model
that isn't hosted in the
cloud I think we're
going to be pretty
helpful to you
thank you very much
that's quite an
interesting talk
actually
I basically have
two questions
essentially
and one is
I can't
quite hear you
sorry
so I think
you'll still get those
kind of errors
the point is
how you
you can kind of
choose how much
access you give
that container to your machine
so for me
I
like everything is in
git and I
like the only way I
can sign commits
is by tapping my
little UB key
so I'm a bit like
go throw git commits
at my git history
it doesn't matter
do you know what I mean
even if I tell
Claude not to
and it does
it doesn't matter
because I can't
push and overwrite
what I've got
so I think
to a limited extent
if the agent
really really wants
to delete the
working directory
on the thing you're
working on
it's going to delete
the working directory
the question is
how far do you want
that blast radius
to possibly be
so it's really
to me about limiting
the damage
and also about not
you talked a lot
about context engineering
I've noticed
Claude Code
does this fun thing
where it asks
if it can read
other places
on your file system
and then gets
all bogged down
in other code bases
that have nothing
to do with
what you're working on
and so putting it
in a box
where it can only
look at the thing
that you wanted
to look at
is kind of handy
just from an
efficiency perspective
as well I think
and so there's
like a win
on both sides
there
no worries
thank you once again Jon